Joyce Mawuse Tawiah

Telephone Mobile:233-24-5046238; 233-20-8861729 E-mail 1: mwtawiah@gmail.com E-mail 2: jtawiah@live.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

To excel in the field of Public Health by taking on roles that challenge my desire to deliver on the task and enable me contribute meaningfully to the success of the Organization whilst, developing my skills by particularly seeking for opportunities to address everyday social behavior which are of public health concerns, pursuing efficiency and effectiveness in all that I set my hands to do with safety as a priority.

SKILLS PROFILE

- Knowledge of monitoring projects and managing its methodologies
- Strong ability to conduct research and analyze data for quality and quantity
- Skilled to prepare and analyze reports
- Proficient in conducting surveys for diverse sectors
- Interpersonal and Communication Skills
- Report Writing Skills
- Results-oriented and possess a service mindset

TRAINING

Constituency Collation Officer, 2024 General Presidential and Parliamentary Elections, 3 December, 2024

Data Quality Monitor: 2023 Integrated Business and Economic Survey, Winneba, 3 – 8, January, 2024

Advanced Short Course on Advocacy for Reproductive Justice in Africa, Afya na Haki Institute, 11-17 Nov. 2023

Statistical Data Management and Analysis using R, Online-Perk Group Africa-Kenya 23-27 Oct. 2023

Data Quality Monitor: 2021 Population and Housing Census, University of Cape Coast, 4 – 14, May, 2021

The Global Challenge of Vector Borne Diseases and How to Control Them, Online-Future Learn Oct. 2020

Managing IRS Operations: A Workshop for IRS Managers and Master Trainers 8 – 13, October 2018

Surveillance, Monitoring and Evaluation, Anglophone Regional Workshop on Surveillance, Monitoring and Evaluation of Malaria Control Programs, School of Public Health-Ghana

11 – 22 June, 2018

Modules:

Introduction to Surveillance, Monitoring and Evaluation Concepts (SME)

Leadership and the role of data in Decision-Making

Designing and Implementing an SME plan

Developing a problem statement and objectives

Frameworks and Indicators

Data Sources, Data Quality, Data management and Analysis, Data Dissemination and Use

Ethics of Malaria SME

Evaluation of malaria programs

Malaria Training, International training course on Planning and Managing malaria control

01 Sept. - 09 Oct. 2015

Modules:

Social and Behaviour Change Communication

Entomology

Case Management

Epidemiology and Monitoring & Evaluation

Planning

Health Economics

Malaria Training, The Mentor Initiative training on Indoor Residual Spraying, Kumasi

08 Jul - 12 Jul, 2013

WORK HISTORY:

AngloGold Ashanti (Ghana) Malaria Control, Obuasi

September 2019 - Date

Data Manager

- Manages 3 sentinel facilities in AngloGold Ashanti (Ghana) Malaria Control Limited
- Monitors spraying activities in sixteen operational districts: eleven in the Upper West Region, three in the Upper
 East Region and two in Ashanti Region
- Ensure timely collation and analysis of malaria data using Excel, Epi Collect 5, Survey Solutions ,R and SPSS for program evaluation
- Consistent tracking of the progress of Indoor Residual Spraying
- Developes data collection tools for the tracking of IRS data and Passive case surveillance
- Weekly IRS report using data visualization tools such as Power BI

Electoral Commission, Obuasi West Constituency

December 2024

Constituency Collation Officer

- Validation of election results on the pink sheet
- Entry of Presidential and Parliamentary Election Results into an Excel Template
- Syncing of data to the Regional and National Database
- Liaised between the constituency coalition team and the regional data quality team on the progress of work

Ghana Statistical Service, Obuasi Municipal and Obuasi East

January 2024 - May 2024

District Data Quality Monitor

- Access District Level Data
- Run batch application to ensure that all structures were uniquely identified
- Generate CSPro error messages/inconsistencies and communicated to field Officers for corrections
- Exported data from CSpro to Stata and R for further processing and reporting
- Liaised between the field team and the regional data quality team on the progress of work
- Monitoring, supervision and validation of listing of Establishments

Ghana Statistical Service, Obuasi Municipal

June 2021 - July 2021

District Data Quality Monitor

- Access District Level Data
- Run batch application to ensure that all structures were uniquely identified
- Generate CSPro error messages/inconsistencies and communicated to field Officers for corrections
- Exported data from CSpro to Stata for further processing and reporting
- Liaised between the field team and the regional data quality team on the progress of work
- Monitoring, supervision and validation of main enumeration

Zonal Monitoring and Evaluation Officer

- Managed 27 sentinel facilities in AngloGold Ashanti (Ghana) Malaria Control Limited
- Monitored spraying activities in nine operational districts in the Upper West Region and two in the Upper East Region
- Ensured timely collation and analysis of malaria data using excel and SPSS for program evaluation
- Consistent tracking of the progress of Indoor Residual Spraying
- Developed data collection tools for the tracking of IRS data and Passive case surveillance

AngloGold Ashanti Malaria Control Limited, Obuasi

Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2015

Zonal Monitoring and Evaluation Coordinator

- Managed 25 sentinel facilities in AngloGold Ashanti (Ghana) Malaria Control Limited
- Monitored spraying activities in eight districts in the Ashanti Region, Central and Western Regions.
- Ensure timely collation and analysis of malaria specific data using excel and SPSS for program evaluation
- Consistent tracking of the progress of Indoor Residual Spraying (IRS)
- Developed data collection tools for the tracking of IRS specific data and Passive Case Surveillance
- Successfully organized one stakeholders meeting, one health workers orientation, six sentinel facility quarterly review meetings and the lead in training of middle level managers in the Monitoring and evaluation department
- Consistently led the onsite data verification team to validate data at the district level
- Posted data in the Malaria Information Surveillance System (MISS), trained national service personnel on how to use the system and also track data in the system

College of Integrated Healthcare, Obuasi

Feb. 2012 - Jan. 2013

Administrator and tutor, Accomplishment

St. Margaret Senior High School, Obuasi

Nov. 2010 - Jan. 2011

Teacher

Health Centre, Adansi-North

May 2010 – Jun. 2010

Health Educator (Field Residency)

Obuasi Government Hospital, Obuasi

Oct. 2008 - Oct. 2009

Assistant Records Technical Officer (National service)

Obuasi Government Hospital, Obuasi Jan - Feb. 2008, Jul. - Aug. 2008, Jul. - Aug. 2007, Aug. 2006

Health Educator (Industrial Attachments)

Nana Amponsah International School, Obuasi

Jul. 2005 – Aug. 2005, Jun. 2004 – Sept. 2004

Teacher

EDUCATION

University of Ghana Dec. 2010

MSc., Applied Health Social Science

University of Ghana Jun. 2008

BSc., Psychology

PERSONAL PROFILE

• Date of Birth: March 12,1985

Nationality: Ghanaian

REFERENCE

Dr. Marshall Kala, School of Continuing and Distance Education-Wa Learning Center, University of Ghana, Legon- Accra, **0201316448**, marshall.kala1@gmail.com

Dr Paul Henry Dsane-Aidoo, Health Specialist, UNICEF, Ghana, 0242141600, pdsaneaidoo@unicef.org

Prof. Emmanuel Asampong, Head, Department of Social and Behavioural Sciences, School of Public Health, University of Ghana, Legon-Accra, **0244278453**, easampong@ug.edu.gh

Mr. Ignatius Williams, Head of Monitoring and Evaluation, AngloGold Ashanti(Ghana) Malaria Control Limited, Obuasi, 0244836456,mensawills@gmail.com, iwilliams@agamal.org